<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <array name="movies_imdb_ids">
        <item>tt0052357</item>
        <item>tt0063522</item>
        <item>tt0072271</item>
        <item>tt0074285</item>
        <item>tt0081455</item>
        <item>tt0086541</item>
        <item>tt0096283</item>
        <item>tt0117571</item>
        <item>tt0166924</item>
        <item>tt0266697</item>
        <item>tt0477348</item>
        <item>tt0816692</item>
    </array>

    <array name="movies_user_ratings">
        <item>8.1</item>
        <item>8.2</item>
        <item>7.8</item>
        <item>9.2</item>
        <item>7.7</item>
        <item>7.8</item>
        <item>9.6</item>
        <item>9.5</item>
        <item>9.8</item>
        <item>9.0</item>
        <item>7.6</item>
        <item>7.5</item>
    </array>

    <array name="movies_user_reviews">
        <item>Over the years, this film has been regarded as one of Hitchcock\'s masterpieces. Its
            been called the most personal, emotional, and complex of Hitchcock\'s films. I agree
            with all of these things except for one, this film IS Hitchcock\'s masterpiece work. All
            of the others pale in comparison to this. There are phenomenal performances here by
            Jimmy Stewart who plays the biggest anti-hero of his career and Kim Novak whose stunning
            beauty and exceptional personalities shine through this dark film. Barbara Bel Geddes
            provides great support as well. Everything about this film, the cinematography, the
            story, the depth, etc. leaves you mystified and transfixed on this dizzying, surreal
            artwork of a film. It truly is flawless. If you are a Hitchcock fan and haven\'t seen
            this you need to get up right now and buy, not rent, this as soon as possible!
        </item>
        <item>When people talk about perfect films I don\'t actually know what they mean. Perfect
            for whom? Perfect compared to what? I think that perfection is in the brain and heart of
            the beholder. "Rosemary\'s baby" is a perfect film to me. Scary in a way that makes you
            breathless. You\'re thinking and feeling throughout the film. One of the many sides of
            Polanski\'s genius is to suggest. And what he suggest is so monstrous that we don\'t
            want to believe it, but we do. The characters are so perfectly drawn that there is no
            cheating involved. John Cassavettes\'s superb study in selfishness and egomaniacal
            frustration is so real that comes to no surprise that he could do what he does to
            advance his career, but we are surprised, we\'re horrified. The spectacular Ruth Gordon
            and Sidney Blackmer are not Deborah Kerr and David Niven, are they? So that they turn
            out to be what they turn out to be is totally believable, but Polanski presents it in
            such a light of normality that you can\'t believe it. Mia Farrow\'s predicament is as
            classic as the boy who cried wolf tale and yet, as told by Roman Polanski in the
            wonderful face of Mia Farrow, is as if we\'re hearing it, seeing it and living it for
            the first time. Every silence, every voice in the distance, every door opening. Your
            heart is always in your throat. There is something there that accelerates a constant
            state of dread. Very few movies have been able to take me to that place, most of them by
            Roman Polanski, what about "The Tenant" or "Repulsion"? Other movies that come to mind:
            David Lynch\'s "Eraserhead" and Martin Donovan\'s "Apartment Zero" But "Rosemary\'s
            baby" stands alone as a terrifying masterpiece.
        </item>
        <item>Let me begin by saying that there are precious few movies that can actually scare the
            crap out of you, and this is one of them. The tension that this movie generates is
            overwhelming at times, and if you watch it with someone who\'s never seen it before, be
            sure to keep your eye on them. You\'ll probably notice a look of disbelief on their
            unsuspecting face.
            Anyone who doesn\'t like being scared will end up being unable to finish this movie.
            People who have a taste for the brutally bizarre will probably hit play again after the
            credits roll. In light of all this, I must also say that in some respects, TCM\'s bark
            is much worse than it\'s bite. Being banned in so many countries for so long, and having
            a title that includes the phrase \'Chainsaw Massacre\', has seemingly led many people to
            believe that there is an undue amount of gore in it. However, there simply isn\'t. Gore
            is not where the scares are in this one. The scares come from the absolutely brutal and
            bizarre scenarios that befall poor Sally Hardesty.
            In closing, I\'d also like to go out on a limb and make the following grandiose
            statement: TCM is the greatest horror film of all time! Not bad for Tobe Hoopers\' first
            effort.
        </item>
        <item>Youthful energy. That\'s what this is -- and what it is about.
            Spacek, King and Depalma are all at their most committed exuberance. Sometimes callow,
            but sometimes so rawly honest one often tingles quite apart from the story. See it on
            this basis alone. DePalma\'s camera has a sense of dance -- Scorcese does too, but
            DePalma\'s is more emotional. Spacek is so clean in her acting that her ability
            frightens. How strange it went away, like a poltergism.
            The story has a haunting tone, also centered on youth and yearning. Menarche as a
            horror, the innocent acceptance/fear of the basest religion, the brash director
            intelligently spoofing Hitchcock. Odd mix that, so an odd and intriguing experience.
        </item>
        <item>Scanners is a film about a group of human mutants that are able to basically make
            people go mad, and finally they can make their minds actually explode. Supposedly
            created out of the scientific work of a scientist working on a product for pregnant
            women(or something like that), the scanners(as they are called) are divided into two
            factions. One is out to destroy all other scanners and the other works for the labs that
            created them. This is an intensely philosophical film filled with many thought-provoking
            questions and issues. Director David Cronenberg again uses the idea of the human body in
            an aberrated state as the focus for terror. He directs with style and suspense, and uses
            a lot more gore in this than most of his previous features. Don\'t let that keep you
            from seeing this film. the acting is solid all around with Stephen Lack giving a nice
            performance in the lead, and Michael Ironsides giving yet another chilling performance
            of dementia. He sure can play one sick and crazy guy! Patrick McGoohan plays the
            fatherly scientist with style and finesse. One of Cronenberg\'s best!
        </item>
        <item>Videodrome is truly a surreal experience. I do not want to include too much
            information as that would spoil the film for "virgin" viewers. If you are familiar with
            Cronenberg\'s work, you may have an inkling of what you\'re in for. Videodrome can drive
            one to the brink of madness, and then tell you you\'ve been there for an hour and a
            half. From scene to scene you can\'t tell what\'s real and what is in James Wood\'s
            imagination. It\'s utter insanity, but it\'s great at the same time. This film is a good
            companion piece with Cronenberg\'s Existenze. When you can wrap the audience up in your
            movie, you have accomplished something few have. And David Cronenberg seems to do that
            time and again. Cronenberg is not for the faint of heart, definitely.
        </item>
        <item>There is no compulsory villain in this wonderfully animated film, no moral lessons, no
            standard blue print story, and the characters will definitely not break out in a song.
            Thank God! It\'s simply a great film for all ages. Don\'t mind if the soundtrack isn\'t
            dubbed to your native language, my kids (4 and 6 years old) could easily follow the
            story with just a few helpers. Japanese is a wonderful language. The film has great
            direction, beautiful backgrounds and a mystical, pleasant aura throughout. There\'s
            nothing like this, I promise you. It\'s idyllic, for the most part, but still with an
            exciting story that unfolds into something very unexpected.
        </item>
        <item>Almost a year after someone raped and killed Sidney Prescott\'s mother in the small
            town of Woodsboro, someone is killing teenagers. When Sidney herself becomes a target,
            the link is apparent and her missing father is a suspect. However, as with all good
            scary movies, everyone is a suspect.

            The film that sparked the revival of horror movies (Halloween H2O, I know what you did
            last summer, Urban Legend etc all followed…..thanks a lot!). This stands out from all
            those (and it\'s lackluster sequels) by being really good and clever. The story is
            nothing more than the standard slasher plot – but it avoids the cliches quite well. In
            fact it uses the cliches as references and makes plenty of jokey references to other
            movies and the supposed rules of horror movies – we even have a quick flash of a
            caretaker dressed in Freddy\'s jumper and hat!

            That doesn\'t mean it\'s not scary – it is! From the tragically horrible opening 10
            minutes through each gory killing the tension is high and the shocks are real. The plot
            twists nicely and the ending is much better than most slasher movies (including the
            absurd endings of 2 and 3). This manages to be fresh, clever and scary – getting by any
            sticking moments with it\'s tongue in it\'s cheek.

            The cats are good – Campbell is a believable virgin, scarred by what happened to her
            mother – before she starts turning into Buffy the vampire slayer in parts 2 and 3. Cox
            is excellent playing against type and David Arquette is funny as the Deputy Sheriff.
            Kennedy as Randy is also funny as the movie geek – in fact he remains the highlight of
            the next 2 films. The cast being filled of up and coming faces (including Ulrich) makes
            it even more thrilling when the `wrong\' people get killed, technically all the cast are
            `unknowns\' who usually make up the body count, so really anyone can potentially get
            offed.

            Overall funny black comedy, scary thrills and gory excitement. A rare treat – a really
            good teen horror movie
        </item>
        <item>Mulholland Dr. is something else. It is a film that will make you question your own
            sanity in many ways. Naomi Watts is the young, starry-eyed Canadian that wants to make
            it big in Hollywood. She is naive and thinks that dreams can come true if you want them
            bad enough. Watts discovers a very beautiful woman with amnesia (Laura Harring in a
            sizzling performance) in her aunt\'s house in L.A. and she becomes determined to help
            Harring out. Harring is mysterious and her near-fatal car crash occurred on the dark and
            winding Mulholland Dr. Throughout several oddball and very dark scenes take place. A
            young director (Justin Theroux) learns that Hollywood is run by strange underworld
            figures that are quiet, but ruthless. Another strange side-story is the mysterious man
            behind the diner that is seen in another character\'s dreams. An inept assassin also
            runs around causing unwanted trouble for himself and others. Then of course there are
            cameos by Robert Forster and Billy Ray Cyrus. The film twists into darkness as it
            progresses as Watts\' and Harring\'s relationship turns sexual. A fine line between
            reality and fantasy is skewered and it comes down to a strange Pandora\'s box that holds
            the true secrets to "Mulholland Dr.". Oscar-nominated director David Lynch also shows
            that not all you see and hear is real, even though one\'s mind might think so. The film
            seems artificial at times, showing Hollywood as a nice place where dreams can come true.
            But then the dreams are turned into vivid nightmares of what could possibly be the true
            reality. David Lynch somehow makes this whole thing work and he makes it work
            beautifully in this reviewer\'s opinion. The film is a trumped-up version of "The
            Twilight Zone" and it adds many techniques that made Alfred Hitchcock the true master of
            suspense. Many wonder what this film is truly about. I am not sure. I am not sure Lynch
            even knows, but I am going to give it a shot. "Mulholland Dr." is the dark side of the
            human condition. It is a film that shows how easy one can lose one\'s soul if bad
            elements are let in. There are figures that seem somewhat supernatural to me in this
            movie. It seems that many of the characters are "messengers" that are all after one
            thing: Naomi Watts\' soul. Watts lets the elements in and in the end she cannot overcome
            them. What she thinks she wants seems attractive on the outside, but there are cobras on
            the inside that will be too strong to fight off. In short, "Mulholland Dr." is a
            brilliant piece of film-making and it is brilliant due to its unique aspects and the
            fact that it is what one thinks it is. There is no right or wrong answer and it is a
            film that makes you think. "Mulholland Dr." is a complicated puzzle for the minds of
            cinema fanatics.
        </item>
        <item>A lot of people have come up to me and said "How can you love Quentin that much, he is
            just too extreme!" or "Oh come on, Kill Bill is just SO not realistic.." Yes. No.
            Mr. Quentin Tarantino is rather extreme, yes, and it\'s lovely! And No. Kill Bill is not
            realistic, but it\'s not meant to be realistic! Just like... Lord of the Rings, that\'s
            not realistic either! But because it has clear unreal elements, like wizards, it\'s
            acceptable?
            You don\'t go to see Kill Bill, or any other Q.T-film to see "Stepmom", in the same way
            you don\'t go to a Marilyn Manson concert hoping that they will play some Spice Girls..
            Kill Bill, both volume 1 and 2, is absolutely gorgeous! The art direction is beautiful!
            The camera angles are perfect... just Gorgeous! The lighting, the sound, the dialogs...
            and of course, the details! No one works with small details the way Quentin does. I must
            also say that the soundtrack is brilliant and the whole film is just so well casted! Uma
            Thurman is perfect in the leading role, Darryl Hannah has never been this good before,
            ever! And Chiaki Kuriyama, even though she has a quite small role, is excellent, even
            better than she is in "Battle Royale". David Carradine is painfully perfect, Michael
            Madsen is ALWAYS excellent, but never as good as when he works with Tarantino. I must
            also say that Sonny Chiba was great. I\'ve never been a big fan of Vivica A Fox until
            now, and I used to think that Lucy Liu was just your average actor but she turned out to
            be fierce. Pretty much everyone who is in this film is ten times better than they\'ve
            ever been.
            But above all things, Kill Bill is artistic, beautiful... Perfect colors, perfect
            everything... gotta love it.
        </item>
        <item>If you like films that literally take your breath away, then this goes to the top of
            the list.
            As stated elsewhere, Javier Bardem is so spectacularly evil and menacing that, if I were
            Mrs Bardem, I\'d be worried about him coming home at night. The man exuded controlled
            evil, and I found myself not breathing when he came onto screen, yet couldn\'t take my
            eyes from him - a truly mesmerising presence.
            Tommy Lee Jones turns in a belter of a performance, and mention should also be made of
            Kelly MacDonald who nails a faultless Texan accent alongside a multi-layered performance
            (despite the paucity of her screen time).
            Beautifully shot, as you would expect, and with some (welcome) moments of humour amongst
            the gore, this is a very very fine film. Miss it at your peril, because when those
            little golden men are being handed out next year in LA, I predict a lot of them will be
            going to this film. A belter.
        </item>
        <item>I was extremely lucky to get the chance to see this film upon its first day release,
            before entering the cinema, my expectations were already high, after all, this was a
            film from the cinematic genius who brought us the likes of \'Inception\' and \'The Dark
            Knight\', to summarise the following review in a single sentence: I left the cinema in
            extreme awe from the visual masterpiece I had just viewed. A film that explores the
            psychological and emotional state of a man whose life revolves around his family,
            \'Interstellar\' is a thrilling and thought-provoking film that boasts an intellectual
            story masterfully written by the Nolan brothers. Whilst there seems to have been
            influence from films like \'2001: A Space Odyssey\' and \'Apollo 13\', \'Interstellar\'
            is unique in its own way. Whilst the subject may be hard to comprehend at times, it
            can\'t be denied how visually monumental and thoughtful Christopher Nolan\'s epic
            science fiction masterpiece is, and can easily be named the best film of this year and
            possibly one of the greatest science fiction films to have ever graced the screen. A
            sheer brilliant feat of cinema.
        </item>
    </array>

</resources>